Ali Hassan

Frontend Web Developer

+92 3367305625

☐ Iamali62426@gmail.com





Meticulous web developer with 1+ year of front end experience building and maintaining responsive and pixel perfect websites and web applications in the recruiting industry. During studying software engineering I found myself specializing in frontend web development and I started my career as a front-end web developer. I strive to put my skills to the test in the professional world and learn new skills every day. Well-versed in Scrum, Agile, how to meet deadlines, and how to document the solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Front End Web Developer

2020 - 2021

WPBrigade (Wordpress development agency)

Key Responsibilities

- Implemented websites, web applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Bringing mock-ups to life using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Maintaining an organized workflow using a project management tool (like GitHub).
- Documenting bug reports, tickets, and any code changes.

Wordpress Developer (Internship)

Mar 2020 - June 2020

SteLogix pvt ltd

Key Responsibilities

- Build websites using wordpress/elementor.
- Prepare website proposals to present to clients.
- Provide technical support to clients.
- Write coding using HTML and CSS.

Certifications

Full Stack Web Developer

Theta Solutions | 2019 – 2019

This certificate is presented to me in recognition of successfully completing advance web development training

Proficiency level: Good

SKILLS

Technical

Html 5 / Css 3

Wordpress / Elementor

Shopify

Bootstrap 4

JavaScript ES6

JS Libraries

JQuery

React Js (Intermediate)

Tools

Visual Studio Code

Bootstrap Studio

Adobe Photoshop

Version Control

GitHub

Languages

English (Professional)

Urdu (Native)

PROJECTS

Restaurant Management Solution

Final Year Project

A Restaurant Management Solution with Admin panel, Tablet web app and Kitchen screen.

Psd to HTML / Psd to Bootstrap / Psd to Wordpress/Elementor

Professional | Open Source

Multiple professional and open source projects which proves my hands on expertise in:

- Psd/Zeplin to html css
- Psd to bootstrap
- Psd/Zeplin to wordpress/elementor
- Shopify

React Js Open Source

Multiple open source projects:

- Covid-19 tracker (API based)
- Amazon clone
- Whatsapp clone
- Receipe search app (API based)
- Youtube clone
- E-commerce website

EDUCATION

Bs Software Engineering 2016 - 2020

University of Management & Technology (2.99/4.00)

Fsc Pre Engineering 2014 - 2016

Punjab Group of College (939/1100) A+

Matric (Science) 2012 - 2013

Dar-e-Argam (929/1100) A+

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Effective communication
- Team player
- Time management

INTRESTES

- Travelling
- Photography
- **Exploring Technology**

